

Dec, 2021 INDORE (M.P.)

Re: Senior Graphic Designer

Dear Sir/Ma'am

It might seem strange that I get excited thinking about colors, typography and cascading style sheets, but my passion for all aspects of graphic design has remained strong throughout my 07-year career. I am very interested in the graphic designer position as you said, and hope to have the chance to interview for this exciting opportunity.

My background includes corporate, agency and freelance graphic design experience, with a history of leading print, interactive and digital design projects to acclaimed completion. I have worked on nationwide and international marketing, advertising, product launch and image campaigns for global brands and companies, as well as a host of startup and mid-size businesses.

Highlights of my skills include:

Print and Digital Graphic Design | Website, UX and UI Design | Packaging Design | Brand Creation and Extension | Interactive Media and Typography Design | Pre-Press and Printing Processes

I am backed by a BA VFX in graphic design and proficiencies in Adobe Creative Suite, Corel Draw and MS OFFICE and a range of other design, video and multimedia software.

Dedicated to bringing brands to life through omni-channel marketing programs, my key focus is to exceed client and employer expectations. I enjoy collaborating with clients, creative teams and production professionals to deliver design solutions propelling web traffic, social media engagement, response rates and customer-acquisition results.

Thank you.

Sincerely, **Anshul Jain**

Enclosure: Resume



Anshul Jain curriculum vitae

Graphic designer translating concepts into impact full, branded designs
Digital Media - Website - UX UI - Video - Print - Packaging - Merchandising - Catalogs - Retail Graphics

ABOUT ME

0

Senior Graphic designer with 7+ Years of experience in the management of the Complete design process, from conceptualization to delivery. Expert at interdepartmental coordination and communication. Skilled with adobe creative suite (illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign, Premiere Pro & after effects), Corel Draw, Microsoft office Suite. and little knowledge of motion graphic and video editing. Able to stretch the boundaries of design and digital storytelling to help my client's brand stand out.



- · Proficient in Customer handling and service
- English, Hindi
- · High level Analytical and Comprehension skills
- Competitive communication skills won numerous awards in debates and essay competitions on both school and college level
- Effective team building and leadership skills. Have handled projects with teams successfully

HOBBIES

SKETCHING, ADVENTURE SPORTS, TREKKING, PHOTOGRAPHY & COOKING



EDUCATION

Graduation

Bachelors of Commerce (Honors) DAVV, Indore 2018

BA VFX ARENA MULTIMEDIA 2015

Senior Secondary MP BOARD 2013

Matriculation
MP BOARD 2011





80%



70%



80%



50% Xd







50%





PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Arena Animation, Sri Aurobindo Institute of technology, Indore

Senior Graphic Designer Trainer, Oct 2020- Nov 2021

- Teaching scratch from industry based requirement to the students
- Act as learning expert when determining, designing, and developing curriculum through research, team member input, and advanced functional/technical knowledge
- Managing all creative work responsibility for SAIT, SAIP, Nordic high international school and Arena Animation Aurobindo
- Working responsibility: Graphic Design Trainer, Sketching Trainer, Photography and cinematography Trainer, Graphic designer and video editor and some of the time helping in counseling for student

Freelance Working, Oct 2019- Aug 2020

 As passionate and experienced senior Designer with a proven track record of successfully leading creative output for projects, and achieving high level client satisfaction. Handling and converting client leads for web design, graphic design (Advertisement media, Packaging, social media creative and UI design)

GOVT. GIRLS COLLAGE,

Graphic Design Trainer, JAN 2019- Aug 2019

- · Design concept
- · Professional Design tools
- · Software Skills Development
- · Industry Overview

Blurb Spot, Indore (M.P.)

Creative Head, Sep 2016 to Dec 2018

- · Generating leads for Marketing solutions
- Client handling
- · Designing of Product as per client need
- · Ensuring timely completion of the product
- · Team management

Thinking Beans Advertising India Pvt Ltd, Indore (M.P.)

Senior Designer, Sep 2015 - Aug 2016

- Taking Project responsibility
- Client handling
- · Branding materials Designing
- Product Designing

Formula One Communication, Indore (M.P.)

Senior Designer, Dec 2014 - July 2015

- Division of work in the team, & ensuring timely submissions
- Overview of the designing
- · Client management
- Recruitment of team and capacity building

MP09 Digital Media, Indore

Designer, May 2014- Nov 2014

- · Preparing designs as per the client call
- Taking approval on the design and make modifications as per supervisor's instructions



DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above are true and best of my knowledge

DATE:

PLACE: INDORE

